# Lev Telyatnikov



### Work Experience

#### Computer Vision Research Fellow, France

Ecole Polytechnique | February 2021 - August 2021

Developed an end-to-end **representation learning** approach for 3D objects symmetry encoding. Obtained latent space <u>has allowed manipulating</u> Intrinsic and Extrinsic symmetry of 3D shapes. Incorporating symmetry information <u>improved the zero-shot classification (2%)</u> as well as object denoising performance (4%).

#### Audio Data Scientist Intern, Italy

Translated | February 2021 - August 2021

Developed a **self-supervised representation learning** pipeline for <u>cross-lingual prosody transfer</u>. Italian <-> English prosody transfer has been achieved (<u>TTS task</u>). Robust Mean Opinion Score score was improved by 5% compared to baseline <u>Tacotron + GST.</u>

#### **NLP Data Scientist Intern, Russia**

Sberbank | June 2020 - December 2020

Deployed **audio denoising** and **speech defects classification** (SPC) into an automated hiring process. Incorporating a <u>metric learning approach into the SPC pipeline improved the f1 score by 4%.</u> The obtained pipeline was integrated into production.

### Education

#### Ph.D. in Data Science

Sapienza University, Rome | November 2021 - November 2024

Research topic: Efficient <u>self-supervised techniques for general audio</u> <u>representation</u> based on human perception.

#### M.Sc. in Data Science

Sapienza University, Rome | September 2019 - October 2021

**GPA: 4.0 - graduated with honors**; Thesis: Latent space of 3D shape manipulation.

#### B.Eng. in Applied mathematics and Computer science

PFUR, Russia | September 2015 - June 2019

GPA: 4.0; Thesis: Lossless audio data compression with enhanced LPC.

# **Projects**

#### **Audio dataset synthes**

In progress | Library: radiomixer, <u>link</u>

The aim of radiomixer is to provide the tool to perform artificial audio data synthesis with the help of radio DJ mixing techniques. It presents advanced control on a fade in/out shapes and duration, overlapping, and other tiny parameters.

#### Recognition of marine seismic data

In progress | Research, link

Seismic diffractions classification to detect Direct Hydrocarbon Indicators

#### **Image Search Engine**

September 2021

Google Training Camp Competition, developed an attention-based image captioning method that uses InceptionV3 and RNN, which won the first place.

#### **Object Detection**

July 2020

Landmark detection and population estimation with the help of satellite images.

### About me

Ph.D. student with research interests in **Deep learning** in the Audio Domain and NLP. Passion about object-centric models and **neural reasoning**. Experienced in representation learning, selfsupervised learning, and other areas. Highly skilled in Deep GCN. RNN. Learning: CNN, Transformers. I am interested in internship research Data Science.

### **Computer Skills**

**Programming Language:** 

Python, R, MATLAB, SQL

#### Frameworks/Libraries:

PyTorch, TensorFlow, OpenCV, scikit-learn, pandas, NumPy

#### Other Software/Tools:

Docker, dvc, AWS, Git, Apache Hadoop, Spark, Docker, MongoDB

# Language Skills

Russian (Native)
English (Advanced, C1)
Italian (Intermediate, B1)

### **Publications**

Linear Prediction Algorithms for Lossless Audio Data Compression.

International Conference on Neuroinfor- matics, 2019. Periodical: Advances in Neural Computation, Machine Learning, and Cognitive Research

# Awards and activity

Winner of Google training campus, 2020 (Image Search engine: CV, NLP) HSE diploma of bachelor research, 2019 (Bachelor diploma research award) Course Computer Vision 2019 Hackathon winner: Breakpoint, 2017

#### References

Assist. Prof. Simone Scardapane Sapienza University, Rome simone.scardapane@uniroma1.it

#### **Director of AI Sébastien Bratières**

Translated, Rome sebastien@translated.net

Professor, Maks Ovsjanikov Ecole Polytechnique, France maks@lix.polytechnique.fr